Sankranti Puja, Rahuri, India
桑格兰提节崇拜
January 14th, 1987
1987年1月14日 印度
Today is the day where we celebrate the change
今天是我们庆祝
towards the tropic of cancer.
北回归线的日子
Tropic of cancer is the one
北回归线
which represents the motherhood,
代表母性
the motherhood of the Earth.
大地的母性
This tropic of Cancer has passed through
跟南回归线不同
quite a big area of land
北回归线
while the tropic of Capricorn has not.
经过大片土地
And the area through which it has passed
它在经过的土地上
it has created
创造彰显
different beautiful manifestation
大地母性的
of the motherhood qualities on this Earth.
各种优美素质
We celebrate this change
我们庆祝这个转变
because the Sun has now moved into the new
因为太阳现在已移向
dimension so that all over the world
新的范围，使全世界
there will be the warmth of the Sun.
都覆盖在它的温暖下
Warmth of the Sun
太阳的温暖
represents the warmth of God's love.
代表神爱的温暖
This is the reason why we celebrate
因此我们庆祝
this festival
这个节日时
by giving you some sort of a sweet
会送上用芝麻
made out of sesame seeds.
制成的糖果
Sesame seeds are given because they are also heat giving
送芝麻是因为它提供热量
and now as we are coming from the cold,
现在寒往暑来
we come to the hot season, in a way hotter season,
某程度上是较热的季节
so to prepare you with that warmth of the Sun.
为了准备迎接太阳的温暖
These special things are made out of the seed
这种特别的食品
of sesame to represent the oncoming warmth
是用芝麻来造，代表将临的暖意
and the warm of the Sun.
和太阳的温暖
Though in India the heat is too much,
虽然印度是非常热
still people are waiting for this time to come in
人们仍然期待这天的来临
and they celebrate it with such a warm heart.
他们以热切的心来庆祝这个日子
At this time it is said that
据说这时候
they give you this sesame seed and the sugar to eat,
他们给你吃芝麻和糖
but now you must speak in a sweet manner,
你必须甜美地说：
"gudd gudd bola", means you must speak in the sweet manner.
"gudd gudd bola"意思是你要说甜美的话
Speaking in the sweet manner is very important.
甜美地说话是非常重要的
Some people think it is smart to speak in a rude manner
有些人以为说话粗鲁很豁达潇洒
or is very intelligent to shout on people,
或向人叫喊很醒目聪明
but no one likes this kind of a personality.
可是没有人喜欢这种行为
You may be intelligent, you may be very sharp or smart,
你可能有聪明才智，可能很机警醒目
maybe on a television people may like to see you,
可能人们只喜欢在电视上看到你
but not as companions, as friends.
他们不会想你成为他们的伴侣和朋友
To speak in a very sweet manner
甜美地说话象征良好教养
is a sign of good breeding, good culture and fear of God.
良好文化和敬畏神
Those who fear God will never speak
敬畏神的人
rudely to another person, because in another person
从不向别人粗鲁地说话
also the same spirit is shining
因为同样的灵也在别人身上发光闪耀
and why should we be sharp or angry with another person
我们为何要向另一个
who is created by God Almighty as we are created.
同样是大能的神所创造的人严厉(sharp)或发怒
So this loving, beautiful relationship
特别是来霎哈嘉瑜伽后
that we have with each other,
我们的关系是
after Sahaja Yoga especially,
充满爱和美丽
let us express in talking to each other sweetly.
让我们用甜美的话来表达这种关系
There are so many ways by which we could be sweet.
有很多方式可使我们甜美
There are little, little things if you do,
很多细微琐碎的事
you can create lot of sweetness,
也能制造甜美
but you need not a sharp tongue, but a sharp memory.
你不需要说话尖锐，但要有敏锐的记忆
I try these things many a times.
我这样子试过很多次
Once one of the Sahaja Yogi,
有一次，一个
who is a very good Sahaja Yogi and an active Sahaja Yogi,
很好很活跃的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
was going in the car with Me
与我一起坐车
and his knife was stolen by the driver or somebody
司机或其他人偷了他的刀
and he got very angry with the driver.
他生司机气
I said, "Forget it, you see he is an poor man,
我说：「算了吧，他是个穷人
so he has taken it away, doesn't matter, just forget it."
所以他偷东西。不要紧，忘记它吧。」
He says, "No, it was because it's a present to me
他说：「不，因为那张刀是
from somebody who was in Switzerland and
一个瑞士人送我的礼物
it's a Swiss knife which I was keeping with me.
是瑞士刀，我经常带着它
So I feel sorry that I have lost it."
失去了它我感到可惜。」
When I went to Switzerland I bought that kind of a
当我到瑞士，我买了
same knife for him.
一模一样的刀给他
When I came, when I gave him,
当我把刀给他时，
he didn't have words to say anything.
他说不出话来
He said, "Mother, how did You remember?
他说：「母亲，你怎么还记得？
After such a long time how did you manage
经过了那么长的时间，你怎样
to get this knife?"
得到这刀子？」
I said, "I have a very good memory."
我说：「我的记忆力很好。」
That's the trouble with Me.
这是我的烦恼
The memory is so good that sometimes,
有时候记忆力好到
I just don't know,
在我不知情下
I may embarrass some people with My memory.
可能会令一些人尴尬
It is that good, I don't forget anything whatsoever.
我的记忆就是这样好，让我不会忘记任何事
I, of course, forget all the bad things,
当然，我忘掉一切坏的事情
because no use remembering bad things,
因为记着它们没用
no use thinking of them.
想着它们也是没用
Because of forgiveness you can always forget the bad things.
由于宽恕的力量，你时常都能忘掉坏的事情
And if you remember the good things
如果你记着好的事情
your joy becomes multiplied.
你的喜乐会倍增
If you try to remember something bad
如果你记着坏事情
then your joy goes down.
你的喜乐会减少
Every time you see a person try to remember
每当你见到任何人，尝试记着
what good that person has done to you.
这人对你做过的好事
What good that person has.
他有什么优点
If you have memory for good things
如果你只记着好的事情
you will have a very nice time.
便会有很美好的时光
Now today is the day when you are all leaving India.
今天你们即将离开印度
Some of you will be leaving day after tomorrow.
有些人后天才走
Whatever it is,
不管如何
I have to tell you one thing, that
我要告诉你们：
whatever was possible has been done here, for you people
任何可以为你们带来喜乐和欢欣的事情
to give you joy and happiness.
在这里都为你们做了
Now when you are going back,
当你回去后
try to remember all that was said to you.
尝试记着所有对你们讲过的话
All that was nice.
记着一切都很美好
How people praised you.
记着人们如何称赞你
How they loved you. How they were kind to you.
如何爱你，如何善待你
How you met some nice people.
你如何遇上好人
What nice experiences you had
如何有美好的经历
but don't brood over things which are worthless.
但不要为无谓的事情担忧
All right, somebody must have said something harsh to you
总会有人对你说一些严厉苛刻的话
or you might have said something harsh to someone,
或你对他人说了些苛刻的话
just forget it.
忘记它吧
Try to understand that you are spoiling
要了解你是在浪费
your chances of enjoying life.
享受生命的机会
Nobody is hurt by that so try to be extremely happy
没有人因此而受伤，所以要极之高兴
that you have met so many people,
你能遇上那么多人
that you have had weddings,
能有婚礼
that you have seen so many weddings.
能出席参与那么多婚礼
We have had a nice time and every bit of it was
我们共渡美好的时光，每时每刻都
full of joyous vibrations.
充满喜乐的能量
Of course, today some of you would be a little unhappy
当然，今天你们部分人会有点不开心
I can understand that because your spouses are leaving,
我能理解，因为你们的另一半要离开
somebody's husbands are going away or
有些人的丈夫要离开
somebody's wives are going away.
有些人的妻子要离开
So I can see some of them
我见到有些人
are looking rather miserable about it.
为此颇为悲伤
But that's a good thing because it is out of love
但这是好事，因为是出于爱
and out of attraction for each other,
出于彼此的吸引力
for enjoying the company of each other.
享受大家结伴同行
That's suggestive of something very good to Me
我认为这是一些很好的事情
but still I would say that, after all,
我要说的是，毕竟
you are going to meet each other
你们会再见面
and remember all the good things that
会记着一切
you have said to each other,
互相说过的好话
you have enjoyed with each other and try to keep happy.
你们互相享受，要怀着喜乐的心情
Because these days will pass very fast.
因为这些日子过得很快
In Sahaja Yoga you just forget time, everything,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，你会忘记时间，忘记一切
the time passes so fast and all these things will pass over
时间飞快地过去，这一切亦会过去
and you will be again united with your husbands or wives,
不管如何，你会再与
whatever may be the case.
你们的丈夫或妻子重聚
So there is nothing to feel very sad about all these things,
所以没有需要为这些事情悲伤
and to keep smiling and laughing,
要保持微笑，继续开怀大笑
so when they are departing also,
好使他们离开看你最后一眼时
they should not feel, see your last face full of tears but,
看到的不是你泪流满面
but remember the face of assurance and courage,
而是记着你一脸自信和勇气
that the hope is there,
期盼着
we are going to meet very soon and
我们很快又再见面
there is nothing to feel very sad about it.
没有什么要悲伤
Today is the day to make joy and to enjoy everything
今天是制造喜乐、享受一切
and to feel the blessings of God all around us.
和感受围绕四周神的祝福的日子
The Sun has come back in His own glory
太阳光荣地回归
and we have to wish Him all success in the coming year,
我们祝愿他在新的一年一切顺利
because in this part of Maharashtra
因为你们都知道，这部分的马哈拉施特拉邦
as you know there has been no rain.
是没有降雨
There has been problems with them and
他们遇到一些问题
we have to wish Him success
我们祝愿
so that He can bring forth the rain
他能成功以太阳的能量
and all that is needed out of this solar energy
为这个国家
that we have in this country.
带来雨水和一切所需
And you have to be beaming like the Sun
当你们回到自己的国家
when you go back to your countries.
要如太阳一般照耀
That your countries are not so hot as ours are neither
你们的国家既没有我们的那么热
you have that much of warmth there and you can find
亦没有那么多温暖，所以你会发现
that why people are so warm and so much loving because
为何人们那么温暖和有爱心
we have the Sun with us.
因为太阳伴着我们
Now you carry the Sun with you and you give them love
现在你们带着太阳，给他们爱
and affection and warmth and let them feel that the Sun
感情和温暖，让他们能感受到你们
has been brought from India by you.
已经把太阳从印度带来
Whenever I have traveled anywhere, in any country,
无论我到哪里，到任何国家
the Sun used to be there very bright, so they said that,
太阳都照得很亮，所以他们说
there is a saying that, when the Indians travel
有一个说法，印度人
they carry the Sun with them.
带着太阳旅游
Of course you can't carry the Sun in your pockets
当然你不能把太阳放在口袋里
but we must be carrying it in our hearts, the Sun.
但我们要心里带着太阳
That must be the reason that's why
这必定是太阳照耀得
the Sun was shining so well
那么好的原因
and everybody came out with their good dresses
人人都穿着好的衣服出来
and everything was ...were, and were enjoying.
万事俱备，都享受着
So this is what it is,
情况就是这样
that you have to carry the Sun with you
今天你们要带着太阳
speaking sweetly today and forever to each other
甜美地说话，永远
to be friendly, to be helpful, to be kind
彼此友善，互助仁爱
because you are yogis,
因为你们都是瑜伽士
you are not ordinary people.
不是普通人
You are yogis, you represent that category of people
你们是瑜伽士，代表着一类
who are known for their righteousness,
正义
for their goodness and for their compassion and love.
良善、慈悲和爱的人
So I wish you all best of luck.
我祝愿你们好运
Enjoy your journeys,
享受你们的旅程
enjoy everything and pass this joy
享受一切，把你们在这里
that you have achieved here,
获得的喜乐
to other people, to other Sahaja Yogis
传播给其他人、其他霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and to other people who are not even Sahaja Yogis.
传播给甚至尚未成为霎哈嘉瑜伽士的人
May God bless you with that.
愿神借着它赐福你们
Shri Mataji speaks in Marathi.
锡吕‧玛塔吉以玛拉地语讲话
Today is an auspicious day and on this day we give sesame
今天是吉祥的日子。在今天，我们给人芝麻
seeds to others and ask them to talk sweetly.
请他们说话甜美
We tell others but it would be better if we tell it
在告诉人要这样做的同时
to ourselves also because it is easier to tell others
最好还是告诉自己，因为叫他人
to talk sweetly but: “I’ll talk harshly.”
说话甜美较容易，但：「我会说话苛刻。」
With this habit of ours have created
我们这种习惯…对自己
wrong ideas about ourselves. We do not have any idea
产生错误的观念。我们不了解
of the blessings that God has bestowed upon us.
神赐予我们什么祝福
God has given such a lot of blessings to us in this country.
神赐予我们这个国家很多祝福
But in this country people do not care much for cleanliness.
可是印度人却不大注重清洁
In this country there are different types of germs
印度有各种细菌
and parasites.
和寄生虫
I feel that we have all the parasites of the whole world
我感到全世界的寄生虫
in this country. We even have parasites which
都在印度，这里甚至有一些其他地区
cannot be found anywhere else in the world.
找不到的寄生虫
If these parasites go to the other countries they will die.
如果这些寄生虫去别的国家，它们会死掉
Because of the cold they cannot survive.
因为它们抵不住寒冷
Due to the Sun, there are so many parasites in this country.
因为太阳，这国家有很多寄生虫
Once a scientist asked Me, “How is it possible to remain
有一次，一个科学家问我：「你的国家
alive with so many parasites present in your country?”
有那么多寄生虫，你怎能生存？」
I replied that “In this country, the people are not only
我回答：「在印度，人们不单
alive but live with joy and happiness,
活着，还活得又喜乐又快乐
with a lot of bliss and happiness.”
充满喜悦和欢欣。」
The reason for this is the Sun.
原因是太阳
The Sun has taught us to keep our homes open
太阳教导我们开放我们的家
and also open our hearts.
开放我们的心
In England, if you have to go out somewhere
在英国，如果你要外出
then you have to spend at least fifteen minutes just to put
最少要花十五分钟
on the right clothes.
穿合适的衣服
It’s as if you are wearing a shield before going out,
就像穿上护甲一样
otherwise you might catch a cold and affect your head.
不然可能会着凉，影响你的头部
This is the situation there.
那里的情况就是这样
Today you are sitting here in the open but we cannot sit
今天你们坐在户外露天的环境
like this in England or in any other Western country.
在英国或其他西方国家我们就不能这样做了
Because of the weather these countries have become very cold.
因为这些国家的天气很冷
Even in our country there are areas (city), for example
即使在印度，也有些地方(城市)，例如
if you go to cities like Bhowali or the other side of
若你到像Bhowali 或另一面的
Nainital and Dehradun and very close to the Himalayas, then
Nainital 和 Dehradun，这些城市很接近喜玛拉雅山
you can find the cold weather as in the other countries.
你会遇到像其他国家的寒冷天气
There, it is also cold like in England and America.
那里像英国和美国那么冷
But in these cold countries not even birds or insects
这些国家，甚至鸟儿或昆虫
can survive.
也不能存活
There are a lot of forests with beautiful flowers in them.
那里有很多长满美丽花朵的森林
They call it a valley of flowers.
他们称作花谷
There are so many beautiful flowers – as if it is a paradise
有很多美丽的花朵 – 就像地球上的天堂
on earth – but this feeling is only for a moment.
但这种美好的感觉只能维持片刻
It is so cold there that we cannot even open our eyes
那里冷得我们甚至不能张开眼睛
to see that beautiful place.
去欣赏这些美丽
We have to wear spectacles otherwise our eyes are hurt,
我们要架上眼镜，否则眼睛会因
because of the cold.
寒冷而受伤
But in spite of the cold,
尽管天气冷
those countries have progressed so much.
这些国家却发展得很快
They have fought against the nature and the cold climate
他们与大自然，与寒冷的气候抗衡
and strengthened their countries.
强化他们的国家
In spite of having a lot of sun, we have not been able
虽然拥有很多阳光，我们并没有
to exploit its advantages.
利用这个优势
We can also produce solar energy.
我们可以生产太阳能
If we use the solar energy we will never have a dearth
如果我们好好利用太阳能
of (electrical) energy.
就不会缺能源
Even the cars can run on solar energy.
即使汽车亦可使用太阳能来行走
But the attention of the politicians here in India
可是印度的政客的注意力
is elsewhere and due to this fact, we cannot exploit
却放在别的事情，我们不但
the advantages from the sun but suffer from it.
没有利用太阳的优势，还反而因此受苦
If we do not go to the extremes then we can do a lot of work.
如果我们不走向极端，便能做很多工作
The main thing which we can learn from the Sun
我们能从太阳主要学懂的
is Its capacity of giving. It always gives.
是施予的能力。它永远都在施予
It does not take anything but always gives.
它不单不拿取什么，还永远都在施予
Due to this tremendous giving power of the Sun
基于太阳这种无比巨大的施予力量
we can have rain, we can have crops and living beings.
我们有雨水，有农作物，有生物
If we did not have the sun then we would not have anything.
如果没有太阳，我们什么也没有
It is due to the giving power of love of the Sun only, that
这全都纯粹源于太阳这种施予的爱的力量
we have been able to reach this state.
我们才能到达这状态
Thus what we have to learn from the Sun is that we should
我们应该向太阳学习
also develop the power of giving.
施予的力量
If we look around us we will find people who will always
便会看到人们常常
think, “How I can save money and keep it for myself?”
想：「我怎样可以为自己省点钱？」
Even if I give money for some programs, some people still
即使我捐款给一些活动，有些人
think how they can save money from that also.
仍会想怎样能省点钱
Even if I have given them some money to spend they always
即使我给他们钱，他们都
have a tendency to save money from everything. Why?
倾向于一切都要省钱。为什么？
Because there is a tendency to hold on to something.
因为他们倾向对一些事情都有保留
If someone goes to the market and they find that prices
若有人到市场，发现
have risen, and if we ask, “Why?” they reply that
加价了，若我们问：「为什么？」他们回答：
“Because the others have increased the prices,
其他人都加价
that’s why I also increase the price.”
因此我也要加价。」
If the (cost) prices of the commodities are not rising then
若来货价没有增加
why do they raise the (selling) price?
为什么出售的货品要加价？
They have always a tendency to suck the energy of others.
他们常常倾向于吸掉他人的能量
Even if I want to make a small ceremony for a festive
即使我想为节日举办
occasion, then others tell Me,
小型庆祝活动，有人告诉我︰
“Shri Mataji you will not be able to succeed.”
「锡吕‧玛塔吉，你办不到。」
When I ask, “Why?” the reply is that people are corrupt and
当我问：「为什么？」答案是人们贪污
they will eat (grab) money.
他们吃(抢)钱
As I eat the food they eat money, so maybe we will not get
我吃食物他们吃钱，或许我们是相处不来
along together. It is such an absurd thing.
这是那么荒谬的事情
Those who are responsible for the country’s welfare,
负责国家的福祉，
those who are the administrators and those on whom the power
负责行政管理，
has been bestowed by God, even they do not understand that
被神赐予权力的人，连他们也
we have to give.
不明白要施予
This quality of giving one has to learn from the Sun:
我们要向太阳学习这种施予的素质
that we have come (on this earth) to give and not to take.
我们来到世上是为了施予而非拿取
This complete change from within has to be reached with
我们要明白，内在的彻底转变
an understanding that we have to give and not to take.
只能透过施予而非拿取才可达致
We have to have the passion of giving.
我们要有施予的热忱
It’s as if when a mother knows that “Today my son is coming”
就如当母亲知道︰「今天我的儿子会来。」
then with passion she thinks, “What can I do for him,
她会热切的想：「我可以为他做些什么
what food can I cook for him?”
可以为他烹调什么食物？」
This is the passion which a mother has.
这是母亲的热忱
Even if she doesn’t have the ingredients, she might borrow
即使她没有食品原料，她会向
them from the neighbors and prepare some sweets for you.
邻居借来为你准备甜食
She always feel that she has not done enough.
她时常感到自己做得不够
Unless and until we have this kind of collective passion
除非我们内在有这种集体的热忱
from inside and have this kind of feeling about others,
这种对他人的感受
no country can progress, neither our own nor other countries.
否则没有国家会进步
But we always have the urge to take things from others,
我们常常有冲动要拿取他人的东西
to plunder from others, to borrow from others or
掠夺他人的东西，向他人借东西
to deceive others. Because of this urge our children
或欺骗他人。因为这种冲动，
will suffer, we will suffer and we will not be able
我们的孩子受苦，我们也受苦，连这个国家
to achieve anything in this country.
也不能有任何成就
In My in-law’s village (inaudible)…to build a lake.
在我姻亲的村子…去建一个湖
The government gave them money in thousands for the purpose.
政府为此给他们数千元
But the lake was never built.
但湖始终没有建成
They said that they had dug a hole to make a lake but then
他们说他们掘了一个洞来建湖
they covered it again since they did not find any water.
因为找不到水，所以封了这个洞
But in fact the hole was never dug.
事实上，从没有掘过洞
So where did the money go?
钱哪里去了？
They sent it to Switzerland (bank).
他们汇往瑞士银行
So the banks will again borrow from Switzerland and send
银行又再从瑞士借钱过来
the money again to Switzerland.
然后再把钱汇回瑞士
If the Sun acts in this way then we cannot survive
若太阳这样做
even for one day.
我们一天也不能活
If he alone eats (consumes) everything, what can we eat?
若他独自吃光(消耗)一切，我们还能吃什么？
Today we are celebrating the SANKRANTI.
今天我们庆祝桑格兰提节(Sankranti)
Sankranti means a sort of Kranti (revolution) by which
Sankranti 即kranti(革命)，藉此我们养成
we acquire the habit of giving.
施予的习惯
Everybody says that we should have the habit of giving
每个人都说我们要有施予的习惯
but most of the people believe in donating something
但大部分人相信捐献
to the priest.
给神父
Also, many people preach the art of giving
很多人宣扬施予的艺术
just to fill their own pockets.
只为自己赚钱
This doesn’t have any meaning.
这些都是没有任何意义
There is always a question of whom to give and why to give.
常常都有施予给谁，为何要施予这些问题
In fact, in all liberty and freedom, we should see
事实上，我们拥有自主自由，我们要看看
for ourselves what we are giving for our country,
自己为国家，为兄弟姊妹，
for our brothers and sisters and our neighbors.
为邻居施予了什么
We should not be selfish, but give with all our heart
我们不应自私，真心的施予
so that we get all the joy of giving.
令我们感受到施予的喜乐
When we give with all our heart, the joy that we get
当我们真心施予
cannot be compared with any other joy.
从中取得的喜乐是其他喜乐没法相比
If we want to feel this kind of joy only, then we should
若你想感受这种喜乐，我们便要今天
celebrate the SANKRANTI today.
庆祝桑格兰提节
Our nature should become like the Sun.
我们的品质要变得像太阳
Whatever he is doing, he doesn’t have the feeling that
不管它做什么，也不会感到
he is doing something. He is doing everything in AKARMA
它在做什么，它做任何事都会是akarma
(without the feeling of doing anything) and constantly
(不感到在做任何事)，不断地
burning himself and giving you joy, light,
燃烧自己，给你喜乐，给你光
the essence of living, and he nourishes you.
给你生命的精粹，还滋润你
We see the Sun every day and many people do Namaskar also,
我们每天都看到太阳，很多人常常namaskar(跪拜)
but we only do Namaskar without imbibing
我们跪拜却没有吸收
his qualities of giving.
它施予的品质
I told you a very small thing:
我告诉你一件小事
that every Sahaja yogi
每一个霎哈嘉瑜伽士
should plant a banyan tree in his garden.
都要在自己的花园种植一棵菩提树
Why do we have to take money from the government
我们为何要为此
for this purpose?
拿政府的钱？
Just to plant a tree and put a fence around that
种植一棵树，再用篱笆围着它
tree doesn’t need much money.
并不需要太多钱
Even to smoke bidi (tobacco) costs more.
即使抽烟花费也比植树多
Try to do this small thing so that others should see that
尝试做这种小事，那么人们便能看到
you are at least doing something.
你至少有做一点事
In spite of this we always think how we can get money
取而代之，我们却常常想可以怎样
from others, how we can plunder others and how we can
拿别人钱，怎样掠夺别人，怎样在别人
save money at others cost.
付出下节省金钱
Because of these tendencies within us,
因为我们有这种倾向
our country can never progress.
国家永远都不会进步
We did not have these tendencies before in people,
过往，我们没有
in the earlier days.
这种倾向
I can tell you that when I was young I saw people who
我告诉你，在我年青时，我看到人们
believed only in giving and never in taking.
只相信施予，不会拿取
I saw them giving only, they did not like taking.
我只看到他们施予，不喜欢拿取
Even the parents did not like it if the children took
即使是父母，也不喜欢他们的孩子
something from others and would tell them to return it.
拿取别人什么，会要他们把东西还给人
I still remember in My father’s house they had made
我仍然记得在我父亲的房子里，他们制造了
some chairs and also an umbrella, out of silver.
一些椅子和雨伞，用银造的
Everybody asked, “Why did you make these out of silver?”
每个人都问︰「你为何要用银来做物料？」
So the reply was, “When we have marriage ceremonies,
答案是︰「当我们庆祝结婚周年
instead of borrowing or hiring them,
除了借用或租用它们
it would be better that we have them with us once
最好还是拥有它们
and for all, because if we had to hire then sometimes
因为若是租来的，有时
we did not get them in time because the earlier person
未必能及时租用，因为之前租用的人
who had borrowed had not returned them.
没有准时归还
And sometimes these umbrellas were lost because someone
有时这些雨伞会遗失，因为还未归还
had never returned them and so they got lost.”
所以它们丢失了
So what I wanted to say is that if we have money,
我想说的是若我们有钱
we should invest it into something collective.
便要集体的投资
If you want to construct a badminton court,
若你想建一个羽毛球馆
then in that court everybody should be able to come
那么每个人都能来玩
and play and we should not say that only my children
我们不应说只有我的孩子
should play in that court. If somebody buys a car,
才能来玩。若有人买了汽车
we should be able to take all the children to school.
我们便能把所有孩子载到学校
Thus we should buy a big car so that all the children
我们要买一部大车，便能把所有孩子
can be taken to school.
载到学校
This habit of being collective and being useful
这种集体的，利于
to everybody, one should learn from the Sun.
每个人的习惯，我们应向太阳学习
And today is a special day when we can learn this thing
今天是特别的日子，我们可以
from the Sun. And we should take a vow that
向太阳学习，我们要承诺︰
“I’ll do something which is collective.”
「我要做一些集体的事情。」
I do not understand how people can eat without caring
我不明白为何有人会
for the common public.
进食时不顾其他人
You do not even worry about your neighbors and do not
你甚至不关心邻居
do anything for the common people.
没有为大家做任何事
I told you a very small thing is to plant a tree.
我告诉你一件小事，就是种植一棵树
We have got so many yogis in Maharashtra,
马哈拉施特拉邦有很多瑜伽士
even if each one plants one tree and looks after it,
即使每个人只种一棵树，照顾一棵树
this will be certainly helpful to everybody.
肯定对每个人都大有帮助
Thus I request all of you to do something collective and
所以我请你们集体的做点事
it will be useful to everybody.
这会对大家都有好处
But one should never think how much will I earn from it
但我们不应想这样我们可以从中获利多少，
and make money out of it.
从中赚取多少
It should not happen like the way we give money
也不应像我们
to the priest.
给钱神父那样
One should open his heart and lovingly do something
我们要开放心扉，以爱为
for the collective and feel the joy out of it.
集体做点事，从中感受个中喜乐
One should make it a habit.
我们要养成这种习惯
I do not want to say that others should have
我不是说
everything for free.
一切都是免费的
I never said that you do something for free for
不是说你要免费为
the people who have come from abroad.
从外地来的人辨事
If you look at them you will see that they have brought
若你看看他们，你会看到他们
so many things for you from abroad to give you as presents.
从外地买了很多物品给你
Of course I have contributed a lot.
当然，我也付出很多
But they have also brought a lot of things of their own.
他们自己也买了很多物品来
When I saw the presents here, I thought that they were
当我看到这里的礼物，我想这是我为你
the presents which I had bought in Rome for you
在罗马购买的礼物
but then they told Me that these were the presents
他们却告诉我，这是
which they bought themselves and they had not
他们买的礼物，他们没有带
brought My presents.
我买的礼物来
They felt such a lot of joy to bring so many things
他们感到为你带来礼物
for you.
是极大的喜乐
They do not even know in Italy to whom these presents were
他们甚至不知道这些礼物在意大利
to be given but they do not bother.
是送给谁，他们就是不介意
They leave it to Me to give them to the Sahaja yogis
他们让我决定这些礼物该送给在印度
here in India.
那些霎哈嘉瑜伽士
But in India we have a tendency to think only about
在印度，我们倾向只想着
our children and about our mother.
我们的孩子，我们的母亲
Then the mother comes walking, limping on one leg.
母亲步行来，用一条腿走来
Then you start saying that “My mother did not get
你便开始说︰「我的母亲没有
a high quality sari.”
好质料的纱丽。」
Since I do not have one I give her a simple sari.
因为我没有，所以我给她一件简单的纱丽
This is the tendency here.
这是这里的倾向
But with the people from abroad it is just the opposite.
但与来自海外的人一起，情况刚刚相反
When they came here they came with so many presents
当他们来，他们带来很多礼物
it seems they brought two tons of presents from abroad.
他们好像从海外带来二吨礼物
Even My hands starting paining while giving these
因为要送出这二吨礼物
two tons of presents.
我的双手开始痛
What I want to say is that they do not expect anything
我是说他们没有期望任何回报
from you. But your behavior should be such as to show
但你的行为要
an example for them. And you should show them that
成为他们的榜样。你要向他们显示
you are in no way inferior to them,
你完全不比他们差
“We are here really to serve you, to welcome you,
我们在这里是为你服务，欢迎你
whatever is possible from our side
不管什么能为你们做的
we do not hesitate to do.”
我们都会毫不犹疑的去做
It doesn’t cost any money nor any hard work.
这样既不花费亦不用努力
The only thing is that we should change our outlook.
唯一我们要做的是改变看法
If even after coming in Sahaja Yoga we are not able
若来霎哈嘉瑜伽后，我们仍未能
to change our nature in this manner then I do not feel
改变我们的品质，我不认为我们能以
that we can change the entire humanity with Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽转化整个人类
The biggest quality in us is to give to others.
我们最重要的品质是能为别人付出
And this quality we should imbibe within us.
我们必须吸收这种品质
In Sahaja yoga your Kundalini is awakened and you
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，你的灵量已被唤醒
realize your spirit but the essence of spirit is like that
你能意识到你的灵。灵的精粹
of the Sun and this essence is of giving.
就像太阳，这个精粹是施予
If you have seen one photograph of Mine, there is the Sun
若你有看过我的一帧相片，我的心
shining on My heart; in fact there is a Sun in My heart
有颗太阳照耀着，事实上，我的心真的有颗太阳
and because of this I never feel that I should take something
因此我从不感到我要拿取你们什么，
from them or to plunder anybody.
又或掠夺你们什么
I do not understand from which part of your head this idea
我不明白要掠夺别人
of plundering them comes from.
这种想法从何而来
This is a very strange behavior.
这是一种很奇怪的行为
Sahaja yogis should not think in this way but on the contrary
霎哈嘉瑜伽士不应有这种想法。相反
every day we must think what we can give or do for others.
每一天，我们都要想我们可以怎样施予，怎样为别人做事
In Rahuri itself I have started an organization
在Rahuri，我开展了一个
whose name is “SAHAJ STREE SUDHAR” or “SAMAJSUDHAR”
名为”SAHAJ STREE SUDHAR”或” SAMAJSUDHAR”
(association for the welfare of women).
(为妇女谋福利的组织)的组织
Through Life Eternal Trust we cannot use the money for
透过基金会，我们不能为妇女的福利
the welfare of the women thus we had to create
而用它的钱，所以我们要成立
this organization.
这个组织
This organization has been registered and people from Canada
这个组织已经注册，来自加拿大
and elsewhere are ready to donate to it but here I do not
和其他地方的人已经准备向它捐款。但在这里
find anybody to work for this organization.
我找不到人为这个组织工作
If the local women take it upon themselves to work for this
若本地妇女能负起这个责任，
organization only then it will succeed.
它便会成功
We have acquired land and all the facilities but we do not
我们已经购买了土地和所有设施，但我们没有
find time to devote for this organization.
为这个组织献出时间
So how can we go to this place?
所以我们怎能到这个地方？
But one should remember that people are coming from abroad
我们要记着，捐款给这个组织的人
with the money to donate for your organization.
是来自海外
They have brought fourteen machines for the women here.
他们为这里的妇女购买了十四部机器
You can see women loitering about without doing anything.
你看到妇女游手好闲
You can ask them to work so that they can earn
你可以叫她们工作，那么她们
something out of it. And they can prosper.
便能赚点钱，也能有点成就
At least these things we should try to think about.
我们最少要想想这些事情
Instead of that we always think about ourselves.
取而代之，我们却只想着自己
So the persons who are in Sahaja Yoga should know that this
在霎哈嘉瑜伽的人要知道
selfish attitude is not accepted in Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽是不容许有这种自私的态度
We should think in terms of global advantage.
我们要想着宇宙的利益
The lives (Vibhouti) of saint are for the salvation
圣人的生命(vibhouti)是为着
of the world. And also for the salvation of saint lives,
拯救世界，也是为着拯救圣人的生命
this world exists.
这个世界才会存在
Thus the saints will be blessed by this attitude…
所以圣人会因为这种态度而受祝福…
(VIBHOUTI means Ashes with which Shiva is decorated).
(vibhouti即湿婆神用作装饰的灰)
Now you have become saints you should behave like saints
现在你已成为圣人，所以你的言行要像圣人
and the first quality of a saint is giving.
圣人最初的品质是施予
You have never heard of a saint plundering anybody.
你从未听过有圣人掠夺别人
If a saint thinks of cheating he does not remain a saint.
若圣人想诈骗，他便不再是圣人
Thus from our side we should always think how much
所以我们应常常想着我们能
we can give and what we can give,
付出多少，付出什么
how much love we can give.
能付出多少爱
And how many people we can help.
能帮助多少人
All our attention should be for this purpose.
我们的注意力全都要放在这个目的上
Nowadays there are welfare associations
现在很多福利机构
just for election purposes.
只为选举而设
We should not create any such type of welfare association.
我们不应创造这种福利机构
But we should create associations in which we can
而是创造我们能
work selflessly and our love should be NIRVAJYA (selfless)
无私的工作的机构，我们的爱应是nirvajya(不自私)
and we should not expect anything in return.
不应期望任何回报
And there are no limits for our love, it is an endless love.
我们的爱是无限的，是无限的爱
When we have this kind of love automatically
一旦拥有这种爱，我们自会
we will know what is to be done.
知道该做些什么
The improvements should be done gradually and every
改善应是渐进的，每一个霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Sahaja yogi should contribute to this collective welfare.
都要为集体的福祉而奉献
We should try to devote our time for this purpose and
为此目的，我们要献出时间
work hard to achieve our goals. It should not happen
努力工作以实现这个目标。不应是
that “Shri Mataji has come, She gives a talk,
锡吕‧玛塔吉来了，她讲话
and when She goes everything is finished.”
一旦她离开了，什么都完结
These people (from abroad) have done a lot.
这些人(来自海外)做了很多工作
They have started schools and social welfare.
他们开展学校，开展社会福利
We should also start something in this manner.
我们也要开展一些同样事情
Sahaja Yoga should not become an association of people
霎哈嘉瑜伽不应是
who have realized the spirit and are swimming in the joy
人们意识到自己的灵，在喜乐中畅泳
but are lazy lumps.
但全都是懒骨头
It should not happen this way.
不应这样
We should try to see how we can help others.
我们要看到自己能怎样帮助别人
We should open our eyes to look around us with love
要张开眼睛，以爱心看四周
and try to see how we can help others.
看看自己能怎样帮助别人
Still I have not been able to move to India.
我仍未能回到印度
Once I come back to India you will see that
一旦我回到印度，你会看到
I will make everyone work.
我能令每个人工作
Thus it is advisable to start working before I come.
因此我建议在我回来前，每个人都要开始工作
Sahaja Yoga is not meant only for sitting and meditating.
霎哈嘉瑜伽不是只坐下来静坐
For meditating why do you need Sahaja Yoga?
若只为静坐，你为何需要霎哈嘉瑜伽？
You can go the Himalayas.
你可以到喜玛拉雅山
If you want to stay here and be in Sahaja Yoga then
若你想留在这里，留在霎哈嘉瑜伽
the common people should be helped by Sahaja Yoga.
那么大众便要得到霎哈嘉瑜伽的帮助
But Sahaja Yoga should not become like these
霎哈嘉瑜伽不应变成这种
modern welfare organizations.
现代福利机构
We should try to achieve our goals with full sincerity
我们要以完全的真诚去实现达成我们的目标
and only then we can say that we have established Sahaja Yoga.
只有这样我们才能说我们已经建立霎哈嘉瑜伽
Now I heard a lot of praise for Me.
我听到很多对我的赞赏
I heard the songs and they gave Me a lot of Joy and
我听到歌曲。他们给我很多喜乐
satisfaction that people have recognized Me.
和满足感，就是人们承认我
But you should remember one thing – you should work
但你要记着，要认识自己，
in order to know yourself because you cannot see
便要工作，因为你不能
yourself in the mirror.
只在镜中看到自己
You should be able to see what you have achieved,
你要看到自己有什么成就
like in the earlier days you used to look after
就像早年，你常常
your household, your children. In the same manner,
照顾家庭，照顾孩子，同样
if you are not able to work for the collective,
若你不能为集体做点事
then in My opinion, you have not achieved anything
我的意见是你透过霎哈嘉瑜伽，完全
through Sahaja Yoga.
没有任何成就
You have remained where you were,
仍然留在原来的位置
you have not progressed at all.
完全没有进步
Next year when I come, you should be able to tell Me
明年当我再来，你要能告诉我
how many banyan trees you have planted.
你种植了多少棵菩提树
Secondly, you should be able to tell Me what collective
其二，你应能告诉我什么集体
or social work you have done.
或社会工作你完成了
If you try to look around you will definitely be able
若你尝试看看四周，你肯定能
to see some collective work which you can do
看到一些你能和你
and you should do.
应做的集体工作
I’m sure you will be able to do it very well.
我肯定你能做得很好
It doesn’t need any money – only you have to decide
不需要花钱，只要真心的
within your heart. When I started Sahaja Yoga,
作出决定。当我开展霎哈嘉瑜伽
at that time I’d given realization to one lady only
那时候，我只给了一个女士自觉
and I started without any money.
开始时我没有钱
I did not have support from anybody but even then
没有任何人支持我，即使是这样
I started Sahaja Yoga.
我仍然开展了霎哈嘉瑜伽
But because of honesty of the work and the consistency,
因为对工作的诚实和坚持，
it has spread so much.
它传扬得很广
Now each one of you, man or woman,
现在你们每一个人，不管男女
you have the responsibility that when you will
都有责任，当你向
introduce Sahaja Yoga to the general public,
大众介绍霎哈嘉瑜伽
you will be able to give them some proof of the general
你要能向他们证明霎哈嘉瑜伽
well being. You need not break any law for this.
对大众有利，为此你不用违规，
You need not do anything wrong nor need you do
不用犯错
anything unlawful. In a very simple way if you just
或做任何不合法的事情。只需以很简单的方式
open your eyes you will be able to see what you can do
若你张开眼睛，便能看到你能
for the general welfare of the people,
为大众福祉做些什么
how you can help the wellbeing of the people.
你怎能帮助人
And I’m here to give you all the strength and energy
我在这里给你所有的力量和能量
to do this work.
去做这工作
We do not need any vote nor any money or anything else.
我们既不需要投票亦不需要花钱，又或需要什么
You should give you Me a promise that without expecting
你只要向我承诺，没有期望
anything in return you will start working for
任何回报，你会开始为
the welfare of the people.
大众的福祉而工作
Sometimes, it might so happen that when people start
有时，当人开展
some welfare work they go round asking for funds.
一些福利的工作，他们会四处找资金
This is wrong. We should not ask for money in the beginning.
这是错的。开始时我们不应要求金钱
First you should start some work which does not need money.
你要先开展不需用钱的工作
Everyone feels that without money we cannot do anything.
每个人都认为没有钱，什么也做不了
You have got the powers so why do you need money?
你已拥有力量，为何还需要钱？
If somebody is sick or not well in your neighborhood
若有人病了，又或你的邻居不舒服
then you can go and visit him and try to soothe that person.
你可以探望他，抚慰他
Instead of that, what I see is that
取而代之，我看到的却是
you bring the sick person to Me.
你把病人带来找我
The other day, someone brought
几天前，有人把一个
an injured person to Me. He had a broken arm.
受伤的人带来，他的手臂断了
A Sahaja yogi could have treated him in two minutes and
霎哈嘉瑜伽士能二分钟内为他医治
made him well but instead of that, they brought him to Me
令他妥当。在公开讲座期间
and that too right in the middle of a public program
他们却带他来找我
and asked Me to treat his arm.
要我医治他的手臂
You are so many and all the powers are flowing
你们这么多人，所有力量
through your hands but still you do not use them.
都在你的双手流通，你们却仍不运用它
If you are not able to treat even these small ailments
若你连这些小毛病也不去医治
what is the use of you being a Sahaja yogi? Someone says,
成为霎哈嘉瑜伽士又有何用？有人说
"my mother is sick, my father has broken his leg.”
我母亲病了，我父亲的腿断了
Instead of bringing them to Me you can easily treat them.
除了把他们带来给我，你能轻而易举医治他们
You do have the powers, try to use them.
你的确拥有力量，试试运用它们吧
Thus you should be able to help the people without
在没有期望任何回报，
expecting anything in return and with full Joy.
完全喜乐下，你应有能力去帮助人
You will be able to feel a lot of joy when you have
当你感到没有做什么
the feeling that you do not do anything but you are just
你只是神的工具时，便会
an instrument of God and you are living in this world,
感到很喜乐，你活在这个世界
in this country and you are giving something special to them.
这个国家，你给予别人一些特别的东西，
It is such a big thing, such a big understanding.
这是种大事情，大的理解
With such a feeling, if all of you decide to work,
透过这种感觉，若你们所有人都决定工作
then, you will be able to do something for others
便能为别人做点事
and other people will see what Sahaja Yoga is.
别人也能看到什么是霎哈嘉瑜伽
Now people think what is Sahaja Yoga –
现在人们以为什么是霎哈嘉瑜伽
just everybody meditating together and that’s all.
只是每个人一起静坐，只是这样
Even if there is some problem in the country Sahaja yogis
即使国家出问题，霎哈嘉瑜伽士
are just sitting in meditation.
也只是静坐
One man came and told Me, “My wife doesn’t cook.”
有人告诉我︰「我的妻子没有煮食。」
I asked, “Why?” He said, “She just meditates.”
我问︰「为什么？」他说︰「她只是静坐。」
So I said, “Is it so? But who told her that?”
我说︰「是这样吗？谁告诉她要这样？」
First she should cook, for meditation even
首先，她要煮食
five minutes are sufficient.
花五分钟静坐就已经足够
I have given you the power and the energy to cook well.
我给你力量和能量去好好煮食
Thus one should have the confidence
因此我们要有信心
that you are capable of work.
你有能力工作
I am giving you the powers, you can assimilate them.
我在给你力量，你能吸收这些力量
If you just meditate every day it is not sufficient.
若你每天只静坐是不足够的
You have to see what wellbeing you are
你要看到你能
giving to the others.
给别人什么福祉
But instead of that, you always think about your own wellbeing
但你却只想着自己的福祉
and come and ask Me to treat your son, your father,
还找我医治你的儿子，你的父亲
your mother, or ask that you should get a good job.
你的母亲，或要我给你一份好工作
And you want that I should also come to your house
你也想我来你的家
to eat, do this, do that.
吃饭，做这些那些事情
This way, you try to impose your will upon Me
这样的话，你想把你的意愿加在我身上
but about you, what can you do?
你能做什么？
You should always remember that you have to do something.
你要常常记着，你要做点事
“I will show Shri Mataji what I’m capable of,
我要向锡吕‧玛塔吉展示我有什么能力
to do something special.”
去做一些特别的事情
We should decide this once and for all.
我们要马上作出决定
I have an image in front of My eyes as Shri Gyaneshwara
我面前有一个形象，Shri Gyaneshwara
has said, "BOLTE PIYUSHANCHE SAGAR."
曾说︰BOLTE PIYUSHANCHE SAGAR
(Words or sayings are like the oceans of nectar)
(说话像海洋的甘露)
Where is it? I want to see it.
这是什么？我想看到它
Thus on this auspicious day I give you
在这个祥瑞的日子，我赐予你
all My sweet blessings that you will help everyone
甜美的祝福，你会帮助每个人
and look after their wellbeing and you will treat
照顾他们的福祉
everyone with love and you will talk sweetly,
会以爱心对待每个人，向他们说美好的话
full of love.
充满爱心对待他们
He is saying you should put your hands
他在说你的手要
like this to say that you are bound by Mother's words.
像这样放，说你要遵守母亲的说话
And we will try to do good to others and
我们要尝试对别人好
we will be very kind to each other.
也要互相友爱
I've been telling them that we have to be collective
我告诉他们不单要与
not among only Sahaja Yogis but with others also.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士合群，也要与其他人合群
We should see surroundings, what's wrong where,
我们要看看四周有什么错
how we can help. We have many social obligations
我们怎能帮忙。我们有很多社会责任
which we have to fulfill.
要实践完成
Now you have reached the stage where you can do that
现在你们已经在
without forming any social organization which collects money
不用建立任何社会组织来收集金钱
and have saints and things that kind of a nonsense.
不用有圣人和做类似的事情下，也能把事情办好
But you can see around yourself who are the needy,
但你要看看四周，有谁有需要
to whom you can help.
有谁需要帮忙
And that is how you can really give
这样你才能真正
a very positive form to Sahaja Yoga.
为霎哈嘉瑜伽带来正面的形象
Marathi
马拉地语
Rahurila
Rahurila
I'll be giving this water to all of you
我把这些水给你们，
all the leaders and aslo..
给领袖，也给…
you can take it.
你可以拿这些水
this water is very good for
它对所有
all diseases of the Mooladhara chakra.
根轮的疾病都很好